Vipinlal RV

Summary

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience. Passionate about technology, learning new things and helping others to work better and more effectively. Currently Senior Software Engineer at InApp.

Technical Competencies

Languages/Technologies : PHP, JavaScript,HTML,Mysql,CSS

Javascript/Frameworks : Angular, JQquery, Node js, React js

Frameworks : Laravel, Codeigniter (2,4), YII, Angular

Database : MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDb

Tools : JIRA, Jenkins, SublimeText, VS Code

Operating Systems : Linux, Windows

Web Servers : Apache

Version Control Tool : GIT

Professional Experience

June 2017 - Present

InApp Information Technologies Pvt Ltd, Trivandrum - Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2017 - June 2017

Bridge Global, Ernakulam -Software Engineer

June 2015 - Feb 2017

Emvigo Technologies, Trivandrum - Junior Software Engineer



Projects Handled

1. WashNRoll

Develop an IOS application that can be used by salesmen for viewing their membership sales, commissions, productivity, membership cancellation and customer retention.

Technology & Tools: Laravel, MongoDB, Git,

Role: Backend API Developer

Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis
- Developing API based on the client requirements
- Development testing and bug fixing

2. AcelmageWear

Ace ImageWear is a family-owned uniform rental company serving businesses throughout Kansas City, Missouri, and Houston, Texas.

Technology & Tools: Laravel, Ajax, jQuery, HTML5, CSS,

Role: Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities:

- End to End Developer of the system
- Developing server-side logic in PHP and MySQL.

3. Opman (Opportunity Management)

Opportunity Interactive is the leader in developing and providing innovative sales, management, and labor-saving technology solutions for the residential and commercial service industries. the mission is to implement technology solutions with our customers enabling them to be more Effective, Efficient and Profitable in their businesses.

Technology & Tools: Codeigniter, Ajax, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, HighCharts

Role: Full Stack Developer



Responsibilities:

- End to End Developer of the system
- Developing server-side logic in PHP and MySQL.

4. KPB - Microfinance Application

Microfinance Solution for managing and disbursing loans for the Microfinance industry. The application will be used for collecting details of the members, surveys, KYC, creating loan products, eligibility for loans, issuing loans, collections, managing funds, reports etc.

Technology & Tools: Laravel 5.5, Jquery, Postgres, Git

Role: Backend API Developer

Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis
- Developing API based on the client requirements
- Development testing and bug fixing

5. WolfPAC - Integrated Risk Management Solutions

The product is an online suite of enterprise risk assessment tools and risk management plans. It is an integrated solution that incorporates various elements of enterprise - wide risks into a single system. It provides a centralized view of risk across people, processes, and technologies in an enterprise.

Technology & Tools: Codeigniter, Ajax, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, HighCharts

Role: Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities:

- End to End Developer of the system
- Developing server-side logic in PHP and MySQL.

6. IBOX - DASHBOARD

The Project is to visualize different data elements in a hospital / medical data to meaningfully arrive at strategic decisions. The dashboards are implemented and live in UK region.

Technology and Tools: Laravel, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Git

Role: Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities:

- End to End Developer of the system
- Developing server-side logic in PHP and MySQL.
- Developing client-side functionality using JavaScript and Jquery.
- Development testing and bug fixing.

Education

BTECH - Sreepathy Institute Of Management and Technology (SPT), Palakkad ,University of Calicut

[March 2010 - March 2014]

XII - Technical Higher Secondary School, Thamarassery, Kerala

[March 2008- March 2010]

X - Perambra Higher Secondary School, Kerala

[March 2008]